https://jfw.ie/privacy-policy-2/

Home Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Who we are
James F. Wallace & Company – Chartered Accountants and Registered Auditors Waterford and JFW Software (“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates the https://jfw.ie website (the “Service”).
This document informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data and is in accordance with the relevant General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) and laws. This Privacy Policy provides you with the relevant information in relation to your rights and our obligations and details as to why, how and when we process your personal data.
This privacy policy applies to the personal data of our clients, suppliers and website users. We reserve the right to amend this policy at any time.
We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.
If you have any queries regarding the personal information we hold or how we store and process it, please contact us:
James F. Wallace & Company,
14 Gladstone Street,
Waterford
Phone: 051 877 155
Email: accountants@jfw.ie
What personal data we collect and why we collect it
Website Users -Comments
When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.
An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.
Media
If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.
Cookies
If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.
If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.
When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.
If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.
Embedded content from other websites
Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.
These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.
How long we retain your data
If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.
For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.
What rights you have over your data
If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.
Where we send your data
Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.
Additional information
Use of client data
James F. Wallace & Company – Chartered Accountants and Registered Auditors Waterford uses the collected data for various purposes:
• To provide and maintain the Service
• To submit the necessary returns to The Revenue Commissioners, The Companies Registration Office and the Central Statistics Office
• To comply with any court ordered requests for information
• To notify you about changes to our Service
• To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when
• you choose to do so
• To provide customer care and support
• To provide analysis or valuable information so that we can improve the
• Service
• To monitor the usage of the Service
• To detect, prevent and address technical issues
Personal data
While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Data”). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:
• Email address
• First name and last name
• Phone number
• Address, State, Province, ZIP/Postal code, City
• Date of Birth
• Personal Public Service Number (PPS) for the purpose of submitting returns to The Revenue Commissioner
• Proof of Identity- to comply with Anti Money Laundering Legislation
• Information relating to financial transactions – for the purpose of preparing your management and or financial accounts
• Bank details for the purpose of processing payments and performing bank reconciliations
• Information relating to your employee’s wages for the purpose of processing Wages and completing your accounts
• Cookies and Usage Data on our website
We collect data that you provide directly to us and data provided to us by relevant third parties such as The Revenue Commissioners, The Companies Registration Office and The Central Statistics Office.
How long will we keep your information for?
James F. Wallace & Company will only retain data relating to your person or business for as long as is necessary to ensure we provide you with the service you require from us. We will retain information relating to your accounts for the period required by law.
Where you have consented to us using your details for direct marketing purposes we will retain such data until you notify us otherwise and /or withdraw your consent.
Transfer of data
James F. Wallace & Company – Chartered Accountants and Registered Auditors Waterford will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place without your prior consent to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.
If you are located outside Ireland and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to Ireland and process it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.
Legal requirements
James F. Wallace & Company – Chartered Accountants and Registered Auditors Waterford may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:
• To comply with a legal obligation
• To protect and defend the rights or property of James F Wallace –
• Chartered Accountants and Registered Auditors Waterford
• To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the
• Service
• To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
• To protect against legal liability
Your rights
You have the right to access any personal data that James F. Wallace & Company processes about you, this is done by submitting a Subject Access Request in writing via post or email. You may request information about:
Use of suppliers data
For the purpose of ensuring that our organisation can manage our relationship with our suppliers it is necessary for us to hold a limited amount of information relating to you, our supplier. We require the contact details of your office and or the relevant individuals that we liaise with to allow use to communicate with you. We also require your bank details to facilitate payments by us to you for products or services you provide.
• What personal data we hold about you
• The purposes of the processing
• The categories of personal data concerned
• The recipients to whom the personal data has /will be disclosed to
• How long we intend to store your personal data
• If we did not collect the data directly from you, information about the source
If you believe that any of the information we hold relating to you may be inaccurate or incomplete, you have the right to ask us to correct that information or to complete the information. We will correct the information as quickly as possible unless there is a valid reason for not doing so, at which point you will be informed.
You have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data or to have your personal data deleted in accordance with The General Data Protection Regulation. You may also object to receiving marketing material from us, exercise your data portability rights and to be informed if we use any automated decision-making processes.
Should you wish to exercise any of these rights, or to withdraw consent to the processing of your information, we will endeavour to respond to your request within one month (subject to any extensions we are lawfully entitled to). Please note that we may keep a record of any communications to help us resolve any issues you may raise.
If we receive a request from you in relation to the above we may ask you to confirm your identity before acting to ensure that your data is protected and secure.
Children’s Privacy
Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (“Children”). We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.
Security of data
The security of your data is important to us but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.
Security providers
We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (“Service Providers”), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analysing how our Service is used.
These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.
Changes to this privacy Policy
We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page. We will let you know via email and/or a prominent notice on our Service, prior to the change becoming effective and update the “effective date” at the top of this Privacy Policy.
You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.
Lodging a complaint
James F. Wallace & Company only processes your personal information in compliance with this privacy notice and in accordance with the relevant data protection laws. If , however you wish to raise a complaint regarding the processing of your information or are unsatisfied with how we have handled you information you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority.
Contact Us
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:
James F. Wallace & Company,
14 Gladstone Street,
Waterford
Phone: 051 877 155
Email: accountants@jfw.ie
Under Article 77 of the GDPR, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Data Protection Commission if you consider that processing of your personal data is contrary to the GDPR. Under Article 78 of the GDPR, you have a right to an effective judicial remedy where the Data Protection Commission does not handle your complaint, or does not inform you within three months on the progress or outcome of your complaint. Under Article 80, you may authorise certain third parties to make a complaint on your behalf. Complaints to the Data Protection Commission should be made in writing and addressed to:
info@dataprotection.ie or
The Data Protection Commissioner, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, Co. Laois.
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue to use this site we will assume that you are happy with it.OkPrivacy policy
